I'm Vinuraj

UI Engineer

rinuvinu77@gmail.com | +91 9677449180



About

I'm a UI Engineer with 4+ years of experience who loves design, code, and coffee. I have a passion for crafting human-computer interaction and believe in building easy-to-maintain websites/apps by breaking them down into its smallest components.

Experience

Web developer, Zoho Corporation

April 2018 - Present 2 year 7 months

- Developing new UI features with interactive user experience
- Writing client-side Javascript and CSS preprocessor SASS
- Building reusable code and components for future use
- Developing customized themes for the application
- Implementing features to improve the user experience and usability
- Ensuring the technical feasibility of UI/UX design

Web developer, Sutherland

November 2016- April 2018 1 year 6 months

- Designed UI from scratch for the product
- Wrote client-side Javascript and CSS for the production
- Assured that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end
- Designed and created multiple modules and reusable components
- Handled client requests using ASP.Net MVC back-end
- · Converting designs into pixel-perfect web pages

Skills

HTML/HTML5

CSS/CSS3

Sassy CSS

JavaScript

React.js

Vue.js

React Native

Education

Bachelor of Technology - Information Technology

Sri Krishna college of Technology - 2013 to 2016

Diploma - Computer Science

Nanjiah lingammal polytechnic college - 2010 to 2013

Products that I have worked on

Zoho Workplace

https://www.zoho.com/workplace

Zoho Workplace is an office suite with nine integrated Zoho apps like Mail, Cliq, Connect, WorkDrive, Show, Sheet, Writer, Meeting and ShowTime. You can access all the apps without switching between browser tabs with the help of a Workplace Dashboard with apps displayed as widgets. Dashboard is customisable and users can rearrange the app widgets and stay connected with the unified interface.

Zoho Mail

https://www.zoho.com/mail/

Zoho Mail is a secure and reliable business email suite for organisations; Zoho mail is integrated with apps like Events, Task, Notes, Contacts and Bookmarks that helps the user to stay organised. It has a asynchronous communication feature called Streams which helps the user to collaborate, socialise and integrate within teams. Users can integrate third-party apps like Asana, Trello etc from the eWidgets panel.

Zoho Mail Control Panel

https://www.zoho.com/mail/control-panel.html

Zoho Mail Control panel helps administrators manage the organisation mailboxes, configure email policies, setup restrictions and customise user information. Administrators can also manage domain details, add spam policies and manage groups from this central space.

Zoho Mail Toolkit

https://zohomail.tools/#domainDetails

This toolkit can be used to troubleshoot or solve email related issues, such as retrieving domain information, looking up registry details, performing port, IP checks and running DNS record checks.